

John Anthony L. Balbin

Software Engineer / QA Specialist

My name is John, a multidisciplinary with over 5 years of experience in the QA industry and Software Testing (manual and automated) with a good understanding of Test Planning, Test Design, Test Execution, Defect Reporting, and Tracking.

Experience

Lead QA, 2021 - Present

SparkPoint Technologies Inc. & MetaGaming Guild

- Ensuring the integrity of SparkPoint's software projects (Exchange, Farms, Pools, Bridge, Launchpad, Airdrop, Wallet, and NFT) prior to launching to production.
- Testing and reporting issues on GitHub.
- Tracking of progress and following up with the devs.
- Prioritization of issues, setting issue severity like critical, normal, low, etc.
- Requirement definition for every project
- Train Junior QA Specialists
- Lead daily scrum meetings

Web Developer, 2020

TechnoPro Engineering, Japan

- Create wireframes, prototypes, style guides, user flows, and communicate ideas.
- Collaborate with other developers in developing the website.
- Present daily output to the team leader.
- Continually updating and maintaining the website.

Software Engineer, 2017-2019

Denso Techno Philippines Inc., Philippines

- Perform source code reviews prior to testing to identify scope.
- Compare source code from the given specification.
- Test pattern design creation
- Perform automated tests
- NG Analysis
- Debugging if there are bugs detected
- Perform self-check and cross-check

Contact

Purok 1 San Vicente St. Sto.
Domingo, Albay, Philippines
+63 949-772-4252
swengr.johnbalbin@gmail.com
https://swengr-janan.github.io/

Education

Bicol University

BS Information Technology 2013 – 2017

Sto. Domingo National High School

High School 2009 – 2013

Sto. Domingo Central School

Grade School 2003 – 2009

Skills

Keen-eyed

Team leadership

Agile development

Critical Thinking

Presentation

Team Player

Asking the Right Questions